<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-07-02T18:54:49+00:00</updated><id>https://egorbronnikov.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Egor Bronnikov</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Daniel Kahneman and Prospect Theory</title><link href="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2024/TRV-Science/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daniel Kahneman and Prospect Theory"/><published>2024-04-09T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-09T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2024/TRV-Science</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2024/TRV-Science/"><![CDATA[<blockquote> <p>Here is <a href="https://www.trv-science.ru/2024/04/pdf401/">my piece</a> published in the Russian popular science newspaper <i><a href="https://www.trv-science.ru/">Troitskiy Variant</a></i>.</p> </blockquote> <p>You can find the note PDF <a href="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/assets/pdf/trv_401N_mine.pdf">here</a>, and the full-issue PDF <a href="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/assets/pdf/trv_401N.pdf">full-issue pdf</a>.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/trv_401N_mine.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The website of the <a href="https://www.trv-science.ru/">Troitskiy Variant</a>. </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="TRV-Science"/><category term="opinion"/><category term="popular"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My note in Troitskiy Variant]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How European Universities Can Counter Russia’s Intellectual Isolation</title><link href="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2023/LSE_EUROP/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How European Universities Can Counter Russia’s Intellectual Isolation"/><published>2023-10-10T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-10T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2023/LSE_EUROP</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2023/LSE_EUROP/"><![CDATA[<blockquote> <p><a href="https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/europpblog/2023/10/10/how-european-universities-can-counter-russias-intellectual-isolation/">This post – which was originally published in the <i>LSE European Politics and Policy</i> – provides an opinion on how European universities can counter Russia’s intellectual isolation.</a></p> </blockquote> <p><em>In April, the Free University of Moscow ceased operating after being labelled an “undesirable organisation” by the Russian government.</em> Egor Bronnikov <em>writes that the targeting of the university is one of the latest examples of Russia turning to intellectual isolation. He suggests that higher education institutions in Europe should redouble their efforts to engage with anti-war Russian students and academics.</em></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/FUM.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The website of the <a href="https://freemoscow.university/?lang=en"> Free University of Moscow</a>. </div> <p>HSE University, previously known as the Higher School of Economics, has been <a href="https://www.topuniversities.com/university-rankings/university-subject-rankings/2022/economics-econometrics?&amp;countries=ru">consistently ranked</a> <a href="https://www.shanghairanking.com/rankings/gras/2022/RS0501">as the best university</a> <a href="https://www.usnews.com/education/best-global-universities/search?region=europe&amp;country=russia&amp;subject=economics-business">in Economics and Social Science in Russia</a> for many years. Despite this, the university has faced escalating political pressures that have resulted in numerous political dismissals of lecturers and professors.</p> <p>In 2020, following a new wave of significant political firings from the university, a group of former professors decided to establish a new university to exist independently of political-administrative pressures from any governmental bodies. This newly-formed, primarily online university was named the <a href="https://freemoscow.university/?lang=en">Free University</a>.</p> <p>Since its inception, the Free University has operated as a tuition-free institution committed to offering academic courses across a wide range of research fields. Given the current political climate, this initiative is of paramount importance as it allows students to remain engaged in global academia. Initially launching with just a few dozen courses during its first semester in 2020, the university had expanded its offerings substantially by autumn 2022, with more than seventy courses voluntarily taught by professors and provided free of charge to students.</p> <p>However, in the spring of 2023, one year after the outbreak of the war in Ukraine, the university’s increasing popularity, coupled with ongoing political repression within Russia, led to the Ministry of Justice labelling it an “<a href="https://www.timeshighereducation.com/news/moscows-free-university-branded-undesirable-kremlin-closes-doors">undesirable organisation</a>.” This label – which has been given to Bard College, Transparency International and Bellingcat, among others – entails two significant consequences: first, legal prohibition on operating in any form within Russia, and second, a high probability of criminal prosecution for all current professors at the university, many of whom are based in Russia.</p> <p>One of the long-term threats for both Russia and the world is the growing tendency toward intellectual isolation, a trend actively promoted by Putin and his government. Currently, the Russian authorities are investing increasing efforts in infiltrating both school and university-level education with pro-Kremlin propaganda. While Putin’s regime, to the detriment of both Russia and the global community, is promoting intellectual isolation, resisting it would constitute an important step in countering the spread of Putinism.</p> <p>One option for doing so would be for other universities to consider hosting already-existing courses that were previously administered by the Free University. There are currently around <a href="https://data.unhcr.org/en/situations/ukraine">6.2 million refugees</a> who have fled the conflict in Ukraine, with <a href="https://data.unhcr.org/en/situations/ukraine">about 5.8 million of these in Europe</a>. There are also around a million people, including political refugees, who have emigrated from Russia. Research suggests <a href="https://www.oecd.org/ukraine-hub/policy-responses/what-we-know-about-the-skills-and-early-labour-market-outcomes-of-refugees-from-ukraine-c7e694aa/">between a third and a half of refugees from Ukraine speak English proficiently</a>, but only a small minority are proficient in other languages. This means several million of these people may struggle to resume their education abroad. Hosting Free University courses in local universities might offer one way to alleviate the burden on local education systems.</p> <p>An alternative option would be for universities to jointly design courses and other initiatives with the Free University that meet the needs of both institutions. Millions of students in Russian universities are seeking high-quality education that is free from propaganda and the therapeutic value of spending even a few hours per week outside a toxic environment should not be underestimated.</p> <p>Finally, universities might consider resuming and expanding academic collaboration with those Russian universities <a href="https://www.eua.eu/news/842:eua-suspends-membership-of-12-russian-universities-following-statement-by-university-leaders.html?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=social-twitter-07-03-2022">that have not supported the war</a>. These universities have faced significant pressure from Russian authorities and need support from the international academic community more than ever. This would be challenging to achieve, but there are some positive examples of adjustments being made, such<a href="https://www.chevening.org/scholarship/russia/"> as the recent exemption for Chevening Scholars from Russia</a> from the previous requirement to return home for two years at the end of their award.</p> <p>These actions could enrich the international academic community by diversifying the student and researcher population, creating opportunities for joint education and research, attracting talent and supporting those in need. But perhaps just as importantly, they would help reduce Russia’s intellectual isolation and thereby contribute to a consistent and strategic effort to confront global threats to democracy.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="LSE-EUROPP"/><category term="opinion"/><category term="opinionpiece"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My Post in the London School of Economics European Politics and Policy]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review of Wellbeing – Science &amp;amp; Policy</title><link href="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2023/LSE_RoB/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review of Wellbeing – Science &amp;amp; Policy"/><published>2023-09-17T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2023/LSE_RoB</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2023/LSE_RoB/"><![CDATA[<blockquote> <p><a href="https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/lsereviewofbooks/2023/09/19/book-review-wellbeing-science-and-policy-richard-layard-jan-emmanuel-de-neve/">This post – which was originally published in the <i>LSE Review of Books</i> – provides a review of <i>Wellbeing: Science &amp; Policy</i> edited by Richard Layard and Jan-Emmanuel De Neve.</a></p> </blockquote> <p><em>In</em> Wellbeing: Science and Policy, Richard Layard <em>and</em> Jan-Emmanuel De Neve <em>present an enquiry into human wellbeing: what factors create it, how can it be effectively measured and how can it be improved? The authors’ rich interdisciplinary examination of how wellbeing can be studied – from sociological research to econometric methods – is a worthwhile read for both experts in the field and newcomers, writes</em> Egor Bronnikov.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/Wellbeing_1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/Wellbeing_2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/Wellbeing_3.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Cover and the Content of <i>Wellbeing: Science and Policy</i> written by Richard Layard and Jan-Emmanuel De Neve (Cambridge University Press, 2023). More information on Cambridge University Press can be found <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/gb/universitypress/subjects/economics/microeconomics/wellbeing-science-and-policy?format=HB">here</a>. </div> <p>Can we obtain a reliable measure of individual wellbeing? Do happier or less happy voters support the incumbent? To what extent is it affected by biological and social factors? Does voter unhappiness lead to populist popularity? A new book – Wellbeing – by Richard Layard, Co-Director of the Community Wellbeing Programme and Emeritus Professor at the London School of Economics, and Jan-Emmanuel De Neve, Professor of Economics and Behavioural Science at the University of Oxford, demonstrates how contemporary empirical and experimental econometric approaches provide us with answers to these and many other questions.</p> <p>The book is divided into four parts. The first part – <em>The Case for Wellbeing</em> – begins by introducing the concept of wellbeing, which refers to how individuals assess their own feelings. It also discusses typical approaches to its quantitative measurement, which have been documented to be robust (chapter one). One of the most common types (known as an evaluative measure) asks individuals to answer the question, “Overall, how satisfied are you with your life nowadays?” by marking their level of satisfaction on a scale from 0 (“not at all satisfied”) to 10 (“very satisfied”). These measurements are crucial for two primary purposes: first, for understanding the determinants of wellbeing; and, second, for creating improvements in wellbeing which should be — and, in many cases, already are — important for individuals, non-profit organisations, businesses, and governments. In the following chapter, the authors provide a concise history of the philosophical and scientific discourse on wellbeing as the overarching societal goal which is enriched with many examples from famous figures (ranging from <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Aristotle">Aristotle</a> to <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Jeremy-Bentham">Jeremy Bentham</a> and from <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Francis-Hutcheson">Francis Hutcheson</a> to <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/John-Rawls">John Rawls</a>).</p> <p>The second part – <em>Human Nature and Wellbeing</em> – directs the reader’s attention to three key clusters. It begins with a depiction of the contemporary understanding of individual decision-making under the influence of cognitive biases (chapter three), where Layard and De Neve introduce issues that hinder individuals from maximising their wellbeing (such as <a href="https://thedecisionlab.com/biases/framing-effect">framing</a>, lack of <a href="https://thedecisionlab.com/reference-guide/philosophy/self-control">self-control</a>, etc.). For example, the authors adeptly introduce <a href="https://thedecisionlab.com/biases/loss-aversion">loss aversion</a>, one of the most crucial concepts in contemporary behavioural economics, by presenting it with simple arithmetic and graphical examples, demystifying the concept. However, this section lacks an exploration of how these human limitations can be leveraged to improve wellbeing (see, for example, <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w18237">a paper by Roland Fryer Jr., Steven Levitt, John List, and Sally Sadoff</a> that demonstrates how loss aversion can be used to enhance the efficacy of teachers’ efforts to increase students’ academic achievements). In the following chapter, the authors rigorously demonstrate how different patterns of thinking interact with human wellbeing. Finally, in chapter five, they delve into neurology and elucidate the interplay between the mind and body, genes and the environment.</p> <p>The third part of the book – <em>How Our Experience Affects Our Wellbeing</em> – constitutes the largest and most elaborate section both in terms of research, the analysis of findings and technical details. It begins with a discussion of overall wellbeing inequality (chapter six). Layard and De Neve – following the style of <em><a href="https://press.princeton.edu/books/paperback/9780691152844/mastering-metrics">Mastering Metrics</a></em> and <em><a href="https://press.princeton.edu/books/paperback/9780691120355/mostly-harmless-econometrics">Mostly Harmless Econometrics</a></em> – present the empirical strategies employed in their research in a way that will be accessible even to novices (chapter seven).</p> <p>Starting from chapter eight, the journey into wellbeing investigation unfolds. The authors explore the dynamics of negative and positive experiences over the course of life for males and females, as well as their heterogeneity across countries (chapter eight). The narrative seamlessly transitions to chapter nine, where research results on the various impacts of schooling, family, and social media are documented. In the tenth chapter, attention is drawn to the still relatively under-addressed issue of mental health, providing evidence on how relatively low-cost programs can significantly improve one’s wellbeing.</p> <p>The next four chapters, devoted to unemployment, work quality, income and community, respectively can be briefly summarised as follows: (i) the psychological impact of losing a job is more severe for wellbeing deterioration than the monetary aspect, and it can have long-lasting effects even after returning to employment, and (ii) while income level is important, it is not the primary factor affecting job satisfaction. Interpersonal relationships and the degree of job interest for an employee surpass income in their influence. The closing fifteenth chapter introduces the role of climate change, directing the reader’s attention to the looming threat for future generations, the potential free-rider problem among countries, and the importance of international agreements.</p> <p>The final part – <em>Government and Wellbeing</em> – delves into the matter of wellbeing in terms of its outcome. This section focuses on three domains: government actions toward wellbeing (chapter sixteen), the relationship between voting and wellbeing (chapter seventeen), and the assessment of costs versus gains in public policy choices (chapter eighteen). Chapter Sixteen holds particular significance due to its crucial societal impact and, therefore, deserves more detailed consideration. Despite the suggestive correlation between happier voters and increased political engagement, research in this field has not yet reached a conclusive relation. Results vary significantly depending on the timeline and socio-political context. In contrast, there is well-documented and robust evidence concerning voting with the incumbent’s presence. Happier voters are much more likely to express their preferences for candidates who are already part of the political landscape and empowered. Furthermore, unhappy voters are more inclined to express their preferences for populist candidates and ideologies (for an extensive discussion of definitions of populism, see <a href="https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/jel.20201595">the paper by Sergei Guriev and Elias Papaioannou</a> published in the <em>Journal of Economic Literature</em>).</p> <p><em>Wellbeing</em> has several advantages. First, it successfully brings together state-of-the-art empirical and experimental research about the factors affecting human wellbeing, which is valuable for both academia and the general public. Secondly, the book encompasses a diverse range of topics, providing overarching discussions on each of them, from the effects of unemployment to the impact of thoughts, and from the role of genes and family to voting behaviour — all in the context of individual wellbeing. Thirdly, Layard and De Neve make extensive use of a significant number of meta-studies (the statistical combination of results from multiple studies) whenever possible, which provides readers with more robust evidence for the authors’ statements.</p> <p>That said, the book has several minor areas warranting critique. The first is a slightly surprising discrepancy in mathematical usage. For instance, the authors frequently employ regression specifications but avoid using the term “derivative,” opting instead for lengthy explanations that span several lines. A more significant downside is the absence of explicit articulation of future research avenues. While several hints in this regard (indicated only by dotted lines) are present in the final part of the book, a more structured discussion from such well-known researchers would be incredibly beneficial.</p> <p>Overall, <em>Wellbeing</em> is a great example of a book that appeals to both experts in the field and newcomers. For the former, it broadens researchers’ perspectives while delving into rich technical detail. For the latter, it provides an excellent introduction to the field, accompanied by an explicit and seamless discussion of various econometric techniques.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="LSE-Review-of-Books"/><category term="books"/><category term="bookreviews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My Post in the London School of Economics Review of Books]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review of A Research Agenda for Experimental Economics</title><link href="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2022/LSE_RoB/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review of A Research Agenda for Experimental Economics"/><published>2022-09-27T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-27T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2022/LSE_RoB</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://egorbronnikov.github.io/blog/2022/LSE_RoB/"><![CDATA[<blockquote> <p><a href="https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/lsereviewofbooks/2022/09/27/book-review-a-research-agenda-for-experimental-economics-edited-by-ananish-chaudhuri/">This post – which was originally published in the <i>LSE Review of Books</i> – provides a review of <i>A Research Agenda for Experimental Economics</i> edited by Ananish Chaudhuri.</a></p> </blockquote> <p><em>In</em> A Research Agenda for Experimental Economics, <em>Ananish Chaudhuri brings together researchers in behavioural economics to explore the contribution of decision-making experiments to social science research. This wide-ranging collection will be of value to both newcomers and experts in the field, writes Egor Bronnikov.</em></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/Res_Agenda_1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/Res_Agenda_2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/Res_Agenda_3.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Cover and the Content of <i>A Research Agenda for Experimental Economics</i> edited by Ananish Chaudhuri (Edward Elgar, 2021). More information on Edward Elgar Publishing can be found <a href="https://www.e-elgar.com/shop/gbp/a-research-agenda-for-experimental-economics-9781789909845.html">here</a>. </div> <p>Previously there was a clear difference between behavioural and experimental economics. Historically, the former attempts to insert psychological insights into neoclassical models, whereas the latter tries to adjust natural science methods of testing human economic behaviour in reduced settings. Nowadays, however, these terms are often used as synonyms and are almost interchangeable. Despite some enduring problems, behavioural and experimental economics have had many achievements in understanding phenomena in ways that were impossible in the framework of standard economics. Examples range from daily life (such as overconfidence in one’s use of <a href="https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/aer.96.3.694">gym memberships</a> or charitable giving behaviour) to sophisticated advice relevant to national policy (for instance, on <a href="https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/0002828042002561">labour market discrimination</a> or <a href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/380085">employee saving</a>).</p> <p>To share the recent advancements in this field, Ananish Chaudhuri, Professor of Experimental Economics at the University of Auckland, curates <a href="https://www.e-elgar.com/shop/gbp/a-research-agenda-for-experimental-economics-9781789909845.html">a new compendium</a> of wide-ranging topics united by one common theme: behavioural economics. Having already published two well-received books (<em><a href="https://www.routledge.com/Experiments-in-Economics-Playing-fair-with-money/Chaudhuri/p/book/9780415476317">Experiments in Economics</a></em> and <em><a href="https://www.routledge.com/Behavioural-Economics-and-Experiments/Chaudhuri/p/book/9780367463939">Behavioural Economics and Experiments</a></em>), Chaudhuri’s new collection aims to present the state-of-the-art achievements of the field, as introduced by academic experts.</p> <p>The book consists of two parts: the first five chapters provide readers with several topics discussed by economics, broadly defined; the following four chapters present a mosaic of subjects adjacent to ‘pure’ economic research areas.</p> <p>The first part of the book elaborates on such topics as social norms, stability of preferences, nudging in the context of environmental regulations, entrepreneurial success, and healthcare. If the first two chapters might be a bit demanding for non-economists (the first requires some very basic knowledge of economic modelling and the second is built on understanding of the Coase Theorem), the other four are accessible for a reader without a background in economics. Are there any stable relations between being a successful entrepreneur and risk and competition preferences? Can a natural disaster change risk perception, trust and altruism? What is the mechanism that leads humans to fail in settling disputes and gets them involved in expensive trials? Which environmental regulation policy is the most effective one? Readers curious about the answers to these questions should give this part of the book their attention.</p> <p>The book’s second section presents a broader perspective on how the methodology of experimental economics can be applied in disciplines ranging from gender studies to neuroscience, political psychology to medicine. Perhaps the most unconventional direction that this part of the book takes is the one presented in Chapter Ten. Written by David L. Dickinson, Professor of Economics at Appalachian State University, this chapter presents an overview of the effects of sleep deprivation on social and economic preferences.</p> <p>Humans exposed to total sleep deprivation the night before the experiment sessions behaved in a significantly different way compared to well-rested subjects. Subjects with total sleep deprivation exhibited both less risk aversion in the risky gains domain and were less risk-loving in the losses domain. Those with deprived sleep showed an inclination towards more antisocial punishment (punishment directed at those who contribute more than the punishing subjects), a decrease in trust and trustworthiness as well as higher levels of miscoordination. This chapter draws a natural yet impressively detailed conclusion: lack of sleep is detrimental not only to an individual’s health but also to society in general.</p> <p>Obviously, there is always a trade-off between completeness, the length of a book and accessibility in terms of the detail provided and the time required to read the volume. Written by researchers working in the respective area, each chapter has the same structure: a general introduction to the particular topic, usually with the motivation of demonstrating its practical importance, and a selective rather than comprehensive literature review.</p> <p>While the first tradeoff — choosing several specific areas within experimental economics — is understandable, the other — preferring eclectic, subjective literature reviews over systematic ones — is more debatable. Of course, one can argue that <em>A Research Agenda for Experimental Economics</em> does not intend to be a handbook, which implies picking papers for the sake of conciseness and readability. However, the book’s approach may still create ambiguity about the grounds for selecting particular papers, and may result in inconclusiveness. It is unclear if this is the effect of the literature itself or the choice of the studies made by the chapters’ authors.</p> <p>A definite advantage of <em>A Research Agenda for Experimental Economics</em> is its focus on the most recent developments in specific areas within behavioural economics. The contributing authors demonstrate both a high level of professional expertise and genuine passion for the featured topics. Another strength of the book is its attempt not only to discuss the current state of research in particular fields, but also to provide readers with future directions. Each chapter elaborates on possible (and sometimes even desirable) avenues within the discussed topic. Overall, this book is a strong illustration of how broad and absorbing economics is and the importance of multidisciplinarity. Furthermore, there is no path dependence in the collection, so if a reader is interested in a particular topic, they can easily delve into it directly.</p> <p><em>A Research Agenda for Experimental Economics</em> sits between being a handbook or textbook and an introduction (in the vein of, for example, <a href="https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/lsereviewofbooks/2017/05/04/book-review-behavioural-economics-a-very-short-introduction-by-michelle-baddeley/"><em>Behavioural Economics</em></a> by Michelle Baddeley). Chaudhuri provides a brief introduction to the principles of contemporary behavioural and experimental economics (discussing the difference between economic and psychological experiments, payment protocols and the validity of external and internal experiments). Yet, the book still requires some acquaintance with economics for readers to fully understand it.</p> <p>Nevertheless, <em>A Research Agenda for Experimental Economics</em> will be of great interest and value for both newcomers and experts. While the former will discover a diverse universe of experimental approaches in economics and the wider social sciences, its results and applications broadening their scientific horizons, the latter will find an area that can provide a new perspective on well-known problems.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="LSE-Review-of-Books"/><category term="books"/><category term="bookreviews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My Post in the London School of Economics Review of Books]]></summary></entry></feed>